In this video, I'm going to be talking about how to set up Sass with webpack,
本节视频将讨论如何在 webpack 上设置 Sass
and some of the particulars about loaders that we haven't looked into yet.
以及一些关于加载器的新内容
As you can see here I've already gone through
可以看到 我已经根据课程内容指导
your first step in this concept and added our loaders.
完成了添加加载器的第一步
Now, this is a different syntax
现在 这里有一段之前没见过的语法 我们来单独讲一下
You can see all of these are in the rules array.
你可以在 rules 数组中看到这些内容
When you see a rule that has a test case and then a use case here,
这里有一个 test 用例还有一个 use 用例
there's a bunch of loaders listed here.
后面是多个加载器组成的列表
That's really different than what we did up here where we were just
这与之前只使用一个 babel-loader
using babel-loader to go over all of our JS files.
处理所有 JS 文件有很大的不同
What are all of these loaders doing here?
这里这些加载器有什么用?
Well, this points to a really cool thing about
这引出了 webpack 加载器一个非常酷的特性 — 支持链式传递
You can have the one loader take the output or you can make one loader run on a CSS file,
可以利用一个加载器的输出 比如说用一个加载器运行 CSS 文件
for instance, or a Sass file.
或 Sass 文件
You can have it take the output that it would generate and
你可以获取加载器生成的输出
instead of just outputting it into the dist folder,
这个输出不仅能输出到 dist 文件夹
actually give it to another loader to process
还可以将其传递给另一个加载器处理
that same information and then that loader can give it to another and another and so on,
然后这个加载器又可以将输出传递给下一个加载器 依此类推
until you get that content to
直到得到分发文件夹最终需要的格式
That can be a little bit of a complex thing to process.
这个处理过程可能有点复杂
So let's take a look at more of what that's doing in detail.
我们来详细看看其中的细节
In our normal loader flow,
在正常的加载器流中
you would have webpack build,
你使用 webpack 构建
so it would run your build dev or build prod.
运行构建开发或构建生产
When you did that,
这样操作时
your file would either match a loader test case or it wouldn't.
你的文件可能与加载器 test 用例匹配或不匹配
If the file being looked at by webpack matches the loader test case,
如果 webpack 发现文件与加载器 test 用例匹配
then the contents of that file is going to get run through the loader,
那么该文件的内容将通过该加载器运行
which could be a babel-loader,
这个加载器可以是 babel-loader
it could be a file loader,
也可以是一个文件加载器
it could be any number of the webpack loaders that exist.
可以是任何已有的 webpack 加载器
But whatever job that loader does, at the end,
但是无论加载器的功能是什么
you're going to end up with new content that
最终都会将原始内容通过某种方式
somehow translated from the original content.
转换为新的内容供你使用
Then your loader is going to add that content into the
然后 加载器会将内容添加到
main.js or whatever you're bundled file is called,
main.js 或任何打包后的文件
and all of that code is what ends up in your distribution folder.
并且所有这些代码最终都将输出到分发文件夹中
But what we're seeing right now is just a little bit different from that
但是现在的流程稍有不同
and this is a simplistic graph of what's going on.
这是简化后的流程图
If you take a look at this part a little more specifically,
如果专门查看这一部分的流程
then we have multiple loaders going on in step three.
会看到第三步中要运行多个加载器
Really what's happening is a file is going to match our loader test case with
这里发生的情况是 文件与加载器 test 用例进行正则匹配
the rejects matter and the contents of that is going to be given to the first loader.
然后将内容交给第一个加载器处理
Once a loader is done with that or it has translated the content into whatever format,
一个加载器处理完成 即已经将内容转换成某种格式后
it's going to give the output to loader 2 and it becomes this assembly line
它会将输出提供给第 2 个加载器 构成这样一条装配线
of changing our content into our desired format which would be the last loader.
直到最后一个加载器将内容转换成我们需要的格式
Now, there are some really tricky things about this.
现在还有一个比较绕的地方
It can make it a little harder to deal with,
不太好理解
but once you know the tricks, it's really easy.
不过只要掌握了窍门 那就很简单了
So chaining loaders is a really powerful tool,
链式加载器是一个非常强大的工具
but you have to know how to use the syntax.
但是你必须知道如何使用其语法
The tricky part is that chained loaders run from right to left. You heard that right.
不太好理解的地方是 链式加载器是从右到左运行的 你没听错
In this case, the Sass loader would be
这样的话 Sass 加载器应该是
the first loader to run and the CSS loader would be the second,
第一个要运行的加载器 而 CSS 加载器是第二个
and the style-loader would be the last and
而样式加载器将是最后一个
it would get all of its content from the CSS loader.
从 CSS 加载器中获取所有内容
That seems a little tricky to me.
对我来说这是有点违反直觉的
I know that it caused me more than a few quizzical looks at
我记得自己第一次学习设置链式加载器时
my computer while I was learning to set all this up the first time,
迷惑不解地确认了好几次
but once you get the hang of it and you remember that trick,
但是一旦绕过这个弯 你就能记住这个窍门
they're really not that bad,
没那么复杂
and you can do some awesome things when you can have
当你具备以任何想要的方式组合多个加载器的能力时
the power to combine multiple loaders in whatever way you want.
就可以完成一些很棒的任务
Also, there's nothing special about any of these loaders.
这些加载器也没有什么特别的
They could be run by themselves or they could be run in a chain.
它们可以单独运行 也可以链式运行
No loader is made just for one specific purpose.
没有哪个加载器在这方面特殊
The other important thing to remember is that the thing that allows us
还有一件重要的事情需要记住
to chain all of these is the "use" keyword here.
使这些加载器链式运行的是这里的 use 关键字
So the use keyword allows us to input an array of loaders,
use 关键字允许我们输入加载器数组
and that's what allows us to chain them.
将数组中的加载器进行链式运行
So with all of that said,
说了这么多
let's try taking a look at how this actually runs.
我们尝试看看实际的运行效果
Given this setup in my webpack dev,
在 webpack 开发配置中加入这个设置
when I run my build script,
当我运行构建脚本时
it should just give me all of my styles inside of my main.js file.
它应该将所有样式放入到 main.js 文件中
So that's what we're going to try,
来尝试运行一下
and when we see our app startup,
当我们看到应用启动时
all of our styles should be present.
所有的样式都应该出现
But we can see that they're not.
但是 可以看到事实并非如此
This is a problem.
这是个问题
I have all of my correct loaders in
我正确设置了所有加载器
place and I have a test case and I have installed all of them,
我也有一个 test 用例并且所有加载器都已安装
and yet somehow none of my styles are here.
但不明原因地 样式都没出现
In fact, if I take a look at my main.js file,
事实上 如果看一下 main.js 文件
there won't even be any styles there.
那里也没有任何样式
That's a problem that maybe you can figure out why it's happening.
这是一个问题 也许你能找到原因所在
See if you can take a look through the code and figure
浏览一下代码 看看能否找出样式没有出现的原因